Guide to the Records of the Lyman R. Bradley Academic Freedom Case RG.19.2
New York University Archives
- Series IV: Related Materials
  - "Academic Freedom and the Cold War: The dismissal of Lyman Bradley from New York Univerisity" by Phillip Deery March 2009. (Box 4, Box-folder 2)
  - Related Periodicals (Box 5)
- Series V. Oversized materials (Box 6)
  - Thermofaxed and microfilm printouts mainly of protests against McCarthyism. (Box 6)
- Series VI: Separated Material (Box 7)
  This series contains materials relative to the Bradley hearing from 1951 including several bound transcripts of the hearing on charges against Professor Lyman R. Bradley, the original stenotype tape of the Bradley hearing, a report of the Faculty Committee, and statements made before the Meeting of the Council of New York University. Further, the series contains an audio recording of a meeting relative to Bradley in the 302 Main Building at New York University from October 11, 1948, Rules of Tenure of American Association of University Professors from 1940, and a report of the Investigating Committee from 1957.
  - Hearing On Charges Against Professor Lyman R. Bradley By Dean Thomas C. Pollock of the Washington Square College, 1951 January 3-5 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Original Stenotype Tape of Bradely Hearing, 1951 January 3-5 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Record of Meeting in 302 Main Building Regarding Bradley, 1948 October 11 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Report of Faculty Committee, 1951 February 26 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Report of Investigating Committee, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Rules of Tenure of the American Association of University Professors, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Statements Made Before Meeting of Council of New York University by Professors Arad Riggs and Fowler Harper, and Dean Thomas Pollock, 1951 March 26 (Box 7, Folder 7)